Hello friends, I am your personal
finance coach Ashok. If you are
looking for a health insurance plan that covers
maternity or OPD,
or you feel that your
health insurance should also cover dental treatment, then
this can be a very good
option for you. So friends, stay tuned
with this video. Today, we will learn about Tata
AEG's Medicare Premium plan. We will know
what its
benefits are, what its features are, and
why this plan is so special. Let's
start the video. Friends, if we
talk about the basic benefits of this plan, then in this
we get time research options ranging from Rs 500,000 to Rs 3 crore. If we
talk about in-patient treatment, then any treatment that is more than 24 hours,
or any hospitalization that is more than 24 hours, will be
free for the injured. If we talk about hospitalization, then
such medical expenses that are incurred
before our hospitalization,
related to this disease, the cost
of this treatment is done on systemic hospitalization basis,
this is
called free hospitalization, so friends.  In this plan,
we can claim charges up to 60 days for pre-hospitalization.
Talking about post-hospitalization, even
after we are discharged from the hospital, a lot of medical expenses continue.
In this plan, for post-hospitalization, we can claim charges up to
90 days for a hospitalization of up to Rs 50 lakh and up to
100 days for a hospitalization of more than Rs 50 lakh.
Apart from this, charges up to Rs 50 lakh are available
for life care procedures.
Friends, life care
procedures are such procedures which, due to
advancement in technology, can be done in a few hours
only. For these,
hospitalization of more than 24 hours is
not required. If we
talk about organ donor in such treatment policy, then the
medical expenses of the organ donor are also quite transparent.
In which plan, if we talk about domicile
hospital or domicile treatment, then
that too is equal to Rs 1000.
Such treatment when we  We get it done at home
or take hospitalization at home
if beds are not available in the hospital near us
or the condition of our patient is
so critical that it
cannot be shifted to the hospital and in such a situation if we have to get
hospitalization done at home then we
call it domestic hospital which is
UPTU Sameshwar Kar Friends in this plan
we get the benefit of UPTU Sameshwar Restore
which is available ten times in taking 2 policy
and up to three times in taking 3 policy
which is triggered
after we consume Inshot on our basis
UPTU
Sameshwar Kar charges are available for AYUSH tax or alternate treatment like
Ayurvedic Yoga Unani Siddha Homeopathy
like in patient treatment now you always have
policy
ambulance tax but for hospitalization friends
now in 250 lakh policy ₹5000 in 75 lakh
policy ₹7500 in one crore policy ₹
10000 in 10 crore policy
Charges up to Rs 30,000 will be available in policies of Rs 20,000 and Rs 3 crore. But if we
talk about hospitalization health checkups, then
now charges of one percent will be available in policies of Rs 250 lakh,
which will be maximum up to Rs
10,000 per policy. Charges
up to Rs 15,000 will be available in a
policy of Rs 75 lakh, up to Rs 20,000 in a
policy of Rs 10,000, up to Rs 25,000 in a policy of Rs 30,000 and up to Rs 25,000 in a policy of Rs 30,000.
Talking about compassionate travel or compassionate visit for free health checkup,
friends, if the treatment of the patient is being done
in some other city
or the plant is out of India, then
ticket charges are available for any one immediate family member to
visit the patient.
In a policy of Rs 250 lakh, up to Rs
20,000, in a policy of Rs 50 lakh,
up to Rs 20,000 and  In policies above ₹50 lakh,
charges of up to ₹50,000 will be
available. Friends, at the
time of hospitalization, there are many such charges
which are not covered by normal health insurance.
These are called consumables,
such as pee kids, syringes, cotton gloves.
Although health insurance does not charge for these, its
benefits are inbuilt in this plan.
Most health
insurances give us a rider on paying a separate premium,
after which
our consumables charges are covered.
Friends, this benefit is inbuilt in this plan.
Apart from this,
we get global tax for the hospital. If we
want to opt out of any treatment, we
can intimate the company in advance and
we can also get treatment outside of India,
for which it will be
available. Friends, in this plan,
charges of up to ₹10000 are available for bariatric surgeries. Bariatric surgery is
for obesity or OBC-related treatment. Another unique
benefit in this plan is that this plan is
present.  Dental treatments are also covered in the treatment,
which
includes treatments like root canal and D extraction.
Apart from this, vaccination tax is also available,
which is currently available. Friends,
many health insurances or rather all
health insurances exclude hearing aids, that is,
diseases related to our ears.
But this
plan covers hearing aids equal to 50% of the actual bill, up to Rs.
10,000 per policy.
Apart from this, if we talk about the daily cash based shared
accommodation benefit, then if we
take shared accommodation, then the company charges us 25%
of the basic benefit, maximum up to Rs. 2,000.
Friends, the cost of our treatment is
associated with our room. The
higher the category of room we take, the higher the
bill we will have to pay for this treatment. In such a situation,
if we take shared accommodation, then the
medical cost of our
treatment gets reduced. In such a situation, the
company wants to give us some reward for this benefit
and that is why
On taking the account, we have to pay a charge of up to ₹2000 to the company.
Apart from this, if the benefit is daily cash
on a company and injured child, friends, if
a minor child is hospitalized
and you take care of him/her, then
you will always have to pay 25% off basic charges up to ₹2000. In this plan,
we also get the option of second opinion.
Friends, if we talk about maternity tax, now
delivery expenses will be available for ₹250 in front of the show-off, ₹50000 for boy child and ₹60000 for girl child and
in the policy above ₹50 lakh, now a charge of ₹1 lakh for
boy child and ₹1.2 lakh will be
available for boy child. Friends, this plan is
a bit unique. It incentivizes us for girl child.
For delivery complications, charges of up to
₹10000 will be available in the policy of ₹50 lakh and up
to ₹25000 will be available in the policy of above ₹50 lakh.
First Air Vaccination  If we are
talking about it then friends,
in all the plans, charges up to Rs. 10,000 for boy child and up to Rs.
15,000 for girl child
are available. There will be prolonged hospitalization.
If the hospitalization is for more than 10 days, then the
company provides us the benefit of prolonged hospitalization. The
next benefit is
hygienist and diagnostics, in which
if there is any treatment according to a free defined list of the company, then for that there are
some charge tables per policy for OPD consultation, in
which the charge will be Rs.
25,000 in a policy less than Rs. 50 lakh and Rs.
250,000
in a policy above Rs. 50 lakh. Talking about OPD treatment, friends, for OPD, charges up to
Rs. 5000 in a policy of Rs. 50 lakh, Rs. 7500 in a policy of Rs. 75 lakh, Rs.
10,000 in a policy of Rs.
15,000 in a policy of Rs.
20,000 in a policy of Rs. 3 crore will be available.
OPD dental treatment  For this, charges up to Rs.
10,000 will be available in a policy of Rs. 50 lakh, Rs.
12,500 in a policy of Rs. 75 lakh, Rs.
15,000 in a policy of Rs. 20,000
in a policy of Rs. 3 lakh and up to Rs. 25,000 in a policy of Rs. 3 lakh. Talking about
emergency and ambulance tax, charges
up to Rs.
5 lakh will be available in a policy of Rs. 250 lakh and
in a policy above Rs. 50 lakh, charges up to Rs. 5 lakh will be available in a non-network
hospital and a network hospital.
Friends, accidental
charges will be very basic and equal to the
maximum up to Rs. 50 lakh.
Talking about home treatment,
friends, there is no home treatment in a policy of Rs. 50 lakh,
but there is a
home care treatment tax in a policy above Rs. 50 lakh,
which includes dialysis at home and
chemotherapy at home. Apart from that,
charges up to 25% will be available for pending care at home.
Friends, if we are talking about cumulative bonus, then
in Islam we have mentioned 50%.
Cumulative bonus is available for every claim-
free year, which will also be reduced in this proportion at the
time of claim. Friends, if we
talk about wellness services, then for that,
unlimited oil consultation general, unlimited
oil concentration specialist health condition
management diet and weight management
program stress management program
video discount on services ambulance
booking facility emergency program
health risk assessment reward earning reward utilization towards
OPD
consultation treatment pharmaceutical health
checkups and diagnostic extras.
Friends, we get two types of discounts in this plan.
If we
add other family members in our plan,
then we get
20% discount in the policy of two family members, 28% discount in the policy of three members and
32% discount in the policy of up to two dependent parents.
Talking about long term discount, we get 5% discount in a two-year policy
and 10% discount in a three-year policy.
Talking about the waiting period, the initial waiting
period  30 days which is common in all policies.
Apart from this, if we talk about listed illnesses
treatment or slow growing diseases, then a
waiting period of 24 months will be applicable for that. A waiting period of
24 months will be applicable for free existing conditions. A waiting period of
48 months will be applicable for maternity. A
waiting period of 24 months will be applicable for OPD treatment and OPD dental treatment as well.
Friends, if we
talk about the medical checkup of the policy, then
in the policy up to Rs 50 lakh, no
medical checkup is necessary till 45 after 45, the tele
medical will be reduced only. In the policy above Rs 50 lakh, there will be
only telemedical till 55 after 45. There will be tele medical from 45 to 55.
After 55, there will be some routine
tests like
Gymnastics, Routine CBC with ESRFT, RFT,
Lipid Profile, TMT, 2D, One Plus One
USG, Abdomen and Pelvis, HBG etc.
Both graphs of Sarai are female and CSF is male at
citras friends this was Tata if you have
any doubt then you can ask by commenting below
you can also purchase your health insurance from us in
which we recommend you the right product according to your
financial and medical condition
also
we have a dedicated team which
helps you step by step in getting the claim so that you do not have to face any problem at the time of claim
friends if you
liked the video then do like it and if
you want to see more such videos
then do subscribe to the channel
because apart from health insurance we
keep making videos on every topic related to life insurance and mutual fund investment personal finance so
you should subscribe to the channel as well as
press the bell icon so that you keep getting
notifications friends that's all for today see you
in the next video
thank you